<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The BBQ Rev</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://thebbqrev.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://thebbqrev.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>The BBQ Rev</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Kohlmeier&#39;s Cooker</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Jon needs a new cooker, and he&#39;s looking for a recomendation. Now, Jon is budget minded. I had been operating on that assumption as I came up with my recomendation, but, at the 11th hour, he&#39;s told me that he&#39;s got a higher budget than I had originally thought. Now, this doesn&#39;t change my initial recomendation, but it does add a second one to this post. So, Jon, here you go:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/351IliQ&#34;&gt;Weber Original Kettle Premium Charcoal Grill, 22-Inch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://product-images.weber.com/Grill-Images/Charcoal/14401001AC_REV.png?auto=compress,format&amp;amp;fit=fill&amp;amp;h=950&amp;amp;w=1000&amp;amp;trim=color&amp;amp;trimtol=10&amp;amp;bg=0FFF&amp;amp;pad=50&#34; alt=&#34;Weber Premium Kettle&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old standby! Yes, this really is a good cooker to have in your arsenal. I&#39;m planning on getting one in the near future. You can grill on this. You can even smoke on this! &lt;em&gt;(Even chicken wings!)&lt;/em&gt; You won&#39;t be able to smoke large batches of meat with this, but you&#39;d still be able to smoke with it. You can probably even cold smoke with it, though that&#39;s only a theory in my head at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, why the premium? Well, there&#39;s a couple reasons for that. First, it&#39;s premium—just kidding! (1) This cooker comes with the hinged cooking grate, which is a must have for smoking with the Weber Kettle. (2) It comes with the one-handed ash  bucket, which is also handy for smoking if you need to clean out ash to help air flow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&#39;s a few other accessories that are super helpful to make this better. The first is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/37kVPcn&#34;&gt;Weber Char-Baskets&lt;/a&gt;. These help keep your charcoal under control and help set up mult zone cooking. The second, which have been on my bucket list for awhile, are &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3jbT8vY&#34;&gt;Grill Grates&lt;/a&gt;. The final one is the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/2Thllat&#34;&gt;Vortex (In)Direct Heat&lt;/a&gt;. This doesn&#39;t just help control where your charcoal goes, but it also creates a high heat, helpful for chicken. You can even get a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3o4mlwv&#34;&gt;rotisserie attachment&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t currently own one of these, but I&#39;ve been around the &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/31kob2F&#34;&gt;Weber Original Kettle&lt;/a&gt; most of my life because that&#39;s what my dad has always had. Now, I just have a &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/3lWPmbD&#34;&gt;Weber Jumbo Joe&lt;/a&gt;, but again I&#39;m looking to upgrade in the near future. And this &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/351IliQ&#34;&gt;Weber Premium Kettle&lt;/a&gt; is top of my list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lowes.com/pd/Oklahoma-Joe-s-Highland-879-sq-in-Black-Charcoal-Horizontal-Smoker/50329703&#34;&gt;Oklahama Joes Highland&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.oklahomajoes.com/media/catalog/product/cache/ade67a2a5fb1e95775b8850c7ff18d43/7/4/7473070a7cb7e917ff0de9c0917906249eec4142_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;Highland Offset Smoker&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I currently own this one. Jon, this is what you want if you prefer smoking meat rather than grilling. This is a true offset smoker, which can double as a grill. To be honest, since I&#39;ve gone down the smoking road, my grill game has suffered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up with a Weber Kettle, grilling has never felt comfortable for me on this smoker. Now, you can put set up charcoal in the cooking chamber for direct grilling. I&#39;ve never been good with burgers on it, though. You can also have cooking grates in the smoke chamber, too. That way you can smoke meat and finish it direct. This, too, has been awkward, and if you&#39;re not careful, the blow back flame doing this can burn your hand. &lt;em&gt;(I know from experience.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve smoked great food on this smoker. I love it. You can&#39;t do much better for an entry level offset. You can modify it some, but some of those can get pricey. It smokes great. It even smoke roasts great, too. That&#39;s what I call it, anyway. I set up charcoal in the cooking chamber towards the firebox end, in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://amzn.to/37kVPcn&#34;&gt;Weber Char-Baskets&lt;/a&gt; of course, and throw some chunks on as well. I cook indirect and then finish direct. Temps at about 350-375°, but I still get great smoke flavor. Now, I&#39;m don&#39;t really cook my steaks to medium rare which I prefer, but they still taste great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All around, this is a great cooker. It&#39;s a bit more hands on, and definitely more in the smoking meat wheelhouse. To be honest, if/when this one rusts out, I&#39;ll probably get another one or even the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.oklahomajoes.com/longhorn-offset-smoker&#34;&gt;Longhorn&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;em&gt;(Though the Yoder &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.yodersmokers.com/backyard/the-cheyenne&#34;&gt;Cheyene&lt;/a&gt; is tempting.)&lt;/em&gt; If you&#39;ve got the budget for it, I wouldn&#39;t say the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.lowes.com/pd/Oklahoma-Joe-s-Highland-879-sq-in-Black-Charcoal-Horizontal-Smoker/50329703&#34;&gt;Oklahama Joes Highland&lt;/a&gt; is a bad choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Either one of these will work for you, Jon. You can smoke a pork butt just as well on the Weber Kettle as you can on the Highland. If you&#39;ve got a big cook coming up, you may just have to do it over a couple days with the kettle. (Or there&#39;s other options, too, to help you plan and manage a larger cook with a smaller cooker.) I know because I&#39;ve smoked a butts on my Highland and Jumbo Joe. You can definitely grill easily on the Weber, and I&#39;m sure you can grill excelently on the Highland. Grilling just isn&#39;t my strong suit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, take your pick, Jon. Each cooker has positives and negatives. But either would suit you nicely. (And thanks for designing the site!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://thebbqrev.com/2020-10-17/kohlmeiers-cooker/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebbqrev.com/2020-10-17/kohlmeiers-cooker/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Honey Sriracha Wings</title>
        <description>&lt;h2&gt;Cook Date: October 10, 2020&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/all-them-wings.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;All Them Wings&#34; width=&#34;80%&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I cooked up wings for myself, along with some boneless wings for my wife and kids. I also prepped the kiddos wings just as simple BBQ using Killer Hogs The BBQ Rub, which you can now pickup at Walmart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;&#34;&gt;Video:&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;em&gt;coming soon!&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Rub&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rating: &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/half-flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;half-flame&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mixed up my own rub for this one. It was a garlic ginger rub. I wanted to add to the Asian theme from the sriracha, which is why there was garlic ginger, along with a few other things in their, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This rub was really good. It smelled great and tasted great. It worked well with the honey sriracha sauce I wipped up. It didn&#39;t exude Asian, but it was delicious nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&#39;t have any coarse ground pepper on hand, so I had to grind it fresh. This made it only slightly a bit spicier than I had expected, along with some more peppery flavor, too. It wasn&#39;t bad, just not sligtly off balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, after a few failed rubs, I didn&#39;t want to blow our tastebuds away with the ginger. I was a little lighter with the ginger than I needed to be. That meant the ginger was very subtle in the background, instead of it being a dominant flavor like a &amp;quot;garlic ginger&amp;quot; rub would suggest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Skinny&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, what did I think? I think this rub was a good start. &lt;em&gt;(Definitely lightyears ahead of my two failed batches.)&lt;/em&gt; That said, I won&#39;t&#39;t use freshly ground pepper again, or we I do, I won&#39;t use quite as much. I also will up the amount of ginger in the rub in order to make it amore domininant flavor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A;l in all, I&#39;ll definitely use this rub again, and I&#39;ll update you on how that turns out. I give the rub a solid &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/half-flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;half-flame&#34;&gt; (smoldering+) rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Sauce&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rating: &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/half-flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;half-flame&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also made a honey sriracha sauce for these wings. I actually based the recipe off of this one at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.saucefanatic.com/honey-sriracha-sauce/&#34;&gt;Sauce Fanatic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&#39;s what I changed. I browned the butter before I added the other ingredients. I wanted to add a little more depth of flavor to the sauce. Based on what we had on hand, my butter was salted and soy sauce reduced sodium. I also added some liquid smoke to make it a little smoker. Here&#39;s what I did:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ingredients&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/4C salted butter (1/2 stick)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/2C honey&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1/3C Sriracha&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2T soy sauce (reduced sodium)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2t lime juice&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2t liqiud smoke&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Instructions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Melt butter in a small pot over medium heat, and brown.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the honey, Sriracha, soy sauce, lime juice, and liquid smoke.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stir until the mixture bubbles gently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simmer longer if a thicker sauce is desired. &lt;em&gt;(I also added cornstarch slury.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove from heat and set aside to cool slightly before storing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was quite tasty. It wasn&#39;t too spicey at all, even my wife liked it. &lt;em&gt;(She doesn&#39;t like spicy food like I do.)&lt;/em&gt; There was a sublte smokiness from the liquid smoke that was very nice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&#39;t think I browned the butter enough. I was rushing to get it done before the kiddos got up, and so next time I&#39;ll definitely give myself more time to brown the butter properly. It was slightly too sweet for my taste, and so I&#39;ll probably reduce the honey a bit and up the Sriracha a tad as well. Finally, I would&#39;ve like a bit more smokiness, so it needed a bit more liquid smoke.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Skinny&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall this is a really good sauce. I will definitely be using it again, with the changes I indicated above. It wasn&#39;t quite a &lt;em&gt;smoking hot&lt;/em&gt; recipe, but oh so close. In the end a &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/half-flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;half-flame&#34;&gt; (smoldering+) rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Cook&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Rating: &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is where this entire meal fell flat. I wanted to smoke the wings for a bit, bread and fry them, and then double dip them in the sauce. Double dip means you fry the wing, spin them in the sauce, char &#39;em up a bit on a grill/flat top, spin them in the sauce again, and serve. It&#39;s a trick I learned during my time in seminary from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cornerpocketfw.com/&#34;&gt;The Corner Pocket&lt;/a&gt; in Ft. Wayne, IN.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Good&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got the offset smoker going really well!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Bad&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pretty much everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Prep&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I prepped too much food. This is the first domino of failure, but I didn&#39;t fully realize it until I got ready for frying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Smoke&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This worked pretty well, but the wings didn&#39;t get smokey at all. Partially because I couldn&#39;t keep the smoke going as I was getting the other steps prepped. They were on for only about 30 minutes before they reached 130°, and then I had to pull them off so they wouldn&#39;t get overcooked when I fried them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Fry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This was a complete failure. I was too pressed for time and space. I didn&#39;t have enough frying space to fry all the wings in a reasonable time. So, I had to call an audbile and fire up my electric smoker to bake most of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used cornstarch mixed with some of the rub. How much? I didn&#39;t measure. I just added enough to tell that there was rub mixed in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn&#39;t dip them properly because I had too many wings (real and boneless) and not enough time. Supper was fast approaching! The batter was too thck and goopy on the wings, especially noticeable for the ones I baked. They looked terrible and their consistancy was also terrible. But they still tasted good!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The corn starch was a bad choice for baking the wings, but it was a great choice for those I did get a chance to fry. They were extra crispy, but I was only able to fry up 3 batches of wings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Double Dip&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This too failed. I mismanaged the fire in my Jumbo Joe, and so the flattop wasn&#39;t hot enough by the time I threw the few wings I was able to get done. Got some carmelezation but not what I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Skinny&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over all this was too much meat not enough time. It was terribly executed. Too many moving parts that I couldn&#39;t manage on my own. I have the feeling this would&#39;ve been great had I planned and executed a smaller batch. They would&#39;ve been smokier, cripsier, better battered, and doubled dipped. They may have been tasty albeit  exectued exceptionally poorly. Because of all these miscues the cook got an up in smoke (&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;) rating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Reflections&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Overal Rating: &lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managing expectations. That&#39;s what I learned. With a growing family, I tried too much. If I go smaller scale with this, it would be easier to handle. Also, I won&#39;t try and fry so much without having the necessary equipment. I will also tweak the breading to account for baking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They tasted great and we ate all the leftovers, so not a complete fail. I fail on the cook, but the flavors were all really good and almost perfect. On the whole, this recipe is smoldering (&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;), but soon I should be able to get it to smoking hot (&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/assets/flame.png&#34; alt=&#34;flame&#34;&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>https://thebbqrev.com/2020-10-14/honey-sriracha-wings/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://thebbqrev.com/2020-10-14/honey-sriracha-wings/</guid>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
